---
courteous:
  jigsaw:
    hurt:
      identifier: creating negative feelings
      quiz:
        - question: Which statement creates less positive feeling?
          option:
            - Why do you dress differently?
            - Why do you look like a frog?
          answer: Why do you look like a frog?
        - question: Which statement creates less positive feeling?
          option:
            - Why are you always so slow getting ready for school?
            - Hurry up!
          answer: Why are you always so slow getting ready for school?
        - question: Which statement creates MORE positive feeling?
          option:
            - These dishes you cooked are unpalatable and look disgusting.
            - You should practice cooking more, and you will cook more delicious dishes than you cook now.
          answer: You should practice cooking more, and you will cook more delicious dishes than you cook now.
        - question: Which statement creates less positive feeling?
          option:
            - It’s none of your business.
            - Don’t worry, I will take care of it, but thank you, anyway.
          answer: It’s none of your business.
        - question: Which statement creates less positive feeling?
          option:
            - Don't throw rubbish on the floor.
            - Please put the trash in the trash can.
          answer: Don't throw rubbish on the floor.
        - question: Which statement creates less positive feeling?
          option:
            - Can you do your homework?
            - Could you please do your homework?
          answer: Can you do your homework?
        - question: Which statement creates less positive feeling?
          option:
            - Don't be impolite next time.
            - Will you apologize for your impoliteness?
          answer: Will you apologize for your impoliteness?
        - question: Which statement creates less positive feeling?
          option:
            - Too bad I don't have time to go to your party.
            - I'm not going to go to your party.
          answer: I'm not going to go to your party.
        - question: Which statement creates less positive feeling?
          option:
            - You can do better.
            - You disappoint me.
          answer: You disappoint me.
        - question: Which statement creates less positive feeling?
          option:
            - (Girl in bedroom to sister) Go out and close the door.
            - (Girl in bedroom to sister) Please close the door when you leave. Thanks.
          answer: (Girl in bedroom to sister) Go out and close the door.
        - question: Which statement creates less positive feeling?
          option:
            - Do you speak English?
            - Can you speak English?
          answer: Can you speak English?
        - question: Which statement creates less positive feeling?
          option:
            - I am very pleased to that you are inviting me to the party, but I have to work that day.
            - Although you are inviting me to the party, I can't go because I have no time.
          answer: Although you are inviting me to the party, I can't go because I have no time.
    hurt_again:
      identifier: creating negative feelings again
      quiz:
        - question: Which statement creates less positive feeling?
          option:
            - May I ask who's calling?
            - Who are you?
          answer: Who are you?
        - question: Which statement creates less positive feeling?
          option:
            - You shouldn't leave your stuff here.
            - Let's not leave our stuff here.
          answer: You shouldn’t leave your stuff here.
passive:
    0:
      identifier: student examples of use of passive in tone
      quiz:
        - question: "'Excuse me, i want to order an chocolate icecream plaese. '<p> Is more diplomatic (make reader feel less bad)"
          option:
            - good example
            - bad example
          answer: bad example
        - question: "'Please be quiet in the museum.' <p> Emphasizes what is important is the object of action, or action itself"
          option:
            - good example
            - bad example
          answer: bad example
        - question: Oil was discovered off Ghana in the 1970s. <p> The person who took the action is unknown
          option:
            - good example
            - bad example
          answer: bad example
        - question: "A: 'The cookies are to be eaten. '<p>Emphasizes both the cookies and eating are important and who eats them isn't important."
          option:
            - good example
            - bad example
          answer: good example
        - question: The bag was sold out in the store.<p> Emphasizes what is important is the action and the object of the action and not the seller of the bags.
          option:
            - good example
            - bad example
          answer: good example
        - question: Under-15-year-olds can’t go to work <p> Emphasizes what is important is the object of action, or action itself
          option:
            - good example
            - bad example
          answer: bad example
        - question: "'The diamond has been stolen' <p>The person who took the action is unknown"
          option:
            - good example
            - bad example
          answer: good example
        - question: "'The law must be observed by the people' <p>Emphasizes what is important is the object of action, or action itself"
          option:
            - good example
            - bad example
          answer: good example
        - question: An apple was eaten by the kids. <p> The person who took the action is unknown.
          option:
            - good example
            - bad example
          answer: bad example
        - question: The whole chocolate cake was eaten by Mary. <p> Emphasizes what is important is the object of action, or action itself
          option:
            - good example
            - bad example
          answer: good example
        - question: "'The book was translated into many languages.' <p>It's not important who took the action."
          option:
            - good example
            - bad example
          answer: good example
        - question: "'Is the Chinese New Year in February this year?' <p>It's not important who took the action."
          option:
            - good example
            - bad example
          answer: bad example
        - question: "'Over 120 different contaminants have been dumped into the river.' <p> The person who took the action is unknown"
          option:
            - good example
            - bad example
          answer: good example
        - question: The glass window was broken by the earthquake. <p> It's not important who took the action
          option:
            - good example
            - bad example
          answer: bad example
        - question: The factory was closed due to a lack of orders. <p> This sentence is not important who took the action.
          option:
            - good example
            - bad example
          answer: good example
sincere:
  description:
    0:
      identifier: explanation of sincere thanks for book token
      questiontext: |+
        How can you tell if someone is sincere? You can't.

        So Dr Bean's decisions that the thoughts of some students were not sincerely felt are without basis.

        He thinks that if someone expressed themselves smoothly and wrote a lot, they were probably _not_ being sincere. And if they wrote simply, or didn't write very much, or didn't express themselves very well, they probably _were_ being sincere.

        In fact, the less sincere Dr Bean felt you were, the higher the goodwill homework score he probably gave you!
    
  jigsaw:
    0:
      identifier: sincere thanks for book token
      quiz:
        - question: "Does Dr Bean think this is sincere:<p> Thank you for the $500 book token.<p> Nuu is a good university and teachers are good.<p> Thanks you, once again, for the book token."
          option:
            - Yes
            - No
          answer: Yes
        - question: "Does Dr Bean think this is sincere:<p>Thank you for giving me a book token worth NT$500.  <p>I have had wonderful life at NUU.  <p>Thanks, again."
          option:
            - Yes
            - No
          answer: Yes
        - question: "Does Dr Bean think this is sincere:<p>Thank you for the book that you send for me, I've already received yesterday.<p>I'm feel very lucky to study in NUU. In NUU , I have learn a lot and meet many great friend. There also have many friendly and great teacher to teach me. If don't have them , I will never be now of me.<p>Thank you again, have a nice day."
          option:
            - Yes
            - No
          answer: No
        - question: "Does Dr Bean think this is sincere:<p>Thanks NUU gives me a book token worth NT$500. <p>NUU is a nice place to study.  I spent so much time enjoy my life in NUU.  <p>Thanks, onces again."
          option:
            - Yes
            - No
          answer: No
        - question: "Does Dr Bean think this is sincere:<p>Thanks everything happened in NUU for these four years. <p>And I'm lucky that everyone I met are friendly.  In these four years, I study hard also play hard. I have many cherish memories in my university life.  <p>Thanks NUU agian, It was really made my life more wonderful."
          option:
            - Yes
            - No
          answer: Yes
        - question: "Does Dr Bean think this is sincere:<p>Thank you for the book Token worth NT$500. I feel happy when receive the book and feel interest withe the book too.  <p>Time pass so fast, I remember the time when I register for year 1, I still like a kids. But now, I'm a graduate student, I have a lots of unforgetable memories in school.  <p>Thanks you, once again, for the book. I'm apperciate the moments in school."
          option:
            - Yes
            - No
          answer: No
        - question: "Does Dr Bean think this is sincere:<p>I am happy to study in NUU. Teacher in the NUU are perfect and nice.  Let me learn a lot of knowledge and have a lot of friends.  <p>So I am thank to school to give me this chance to get the Token."
          option:
            - Yes
            - No
          answer: Yes
        - question: "Does Dr Bean think this is sincere:<p>Thank you for giving me the book worth. It really help me a lot.  <p>Before i was a top student, i study without experience by my own, NUU is the place i solve my question and problem.  <p>Thank you once again, for your time."
          option:
            - Yes
            - No
          answer: Yes
        - question: "Does Dr Bean think this is sincere:<p>Thank for the book token, I am glad to accept this gift. <p>I want to thank my profession to teach our knowledge and some special in the class.  In the school, I can get lots of experience from the techers and students. I joined some special club and also faced some difficult proplem. I am thank for our school to give me many chance to do some differience.  <p>Finally I want to thank this NUU, it is great place to make strong and smart."
          option:
            - Yes
            - No
          answer: No
        - question: "Does Dr Bean think this is sincere:<p>Thank you for giving me a book token worth NT$500. It's a good life in NUU.    <p>In the first time to be NUU, it has great enviroment for study and kind students and teachers.    <p>Thanks, once again."
          option:
            - Yes
            - No
          answer: No
conditional:
  jigsaw:
    0:
      identifier: student conditional examples
      quiz:
        - question: What will you do if Dr Bean comes up behind you and looks at your computer screen.
          option:
            - Type 0
            - Type 1
            - Type 2
            - Type 3
          answer: Type 1
        - question: If I make a big fortune, I can travel around the world.
          option:
            - Type 0
            - Type 1
            - Type 2
            - Type 3
          answer: Type 1
        - question: If I knew a person was very emotional, I would not agree to go on a date with him/her.
          option:
            - Type 0
            - Type 1
            - Type 2
            - Type 3
          answer: Type 2
        - question: If I had read the recipe carefully, I would have cooked my dinner better.
          option:
            - Type 0
            - Type 1
            - Type 2
            - Type 3
          answer: Type 3
        - question: If I had known the answer I would not have gotten the question wrong.
          option:
            - Type 0
            - Type 1
            - Type 2
            - Type 3
          answer: Type 3
        - question: If I had known the answer I would not have asked the question.
          option:
            - Type 0
            - Type 1
            - Type 2
            - Type 3
          answer: Type 3
        - question: You can do well if you work hard.
          option:
            - Type 0
            - Type 1
            - Type 2
            - Type 3
          answer: Type 1
        - question: He could do well if he worked hard.
          option:
            - Type 0
            - Type 1
            - Type 2
            - Type 3
          answer: Type 2
        - question: I would have had a good grade, if I had worked hard.
          option:
            - Type 0
            - Type 1
            - Type 2
            - Type 3
          answer: Type 3
        - question: If I have time, I'll go to your party.
          option:
            - Type 0
            - Type 1
            - Type 2
            - Type 3
          answer: Type 1
        - question:  If I was your boyfriend, I'd never let you go,
          option:
            - Type 0
            - Type 1
            - Type 2
            - Type 3
          answer: Type 2
        - question:  If I had known it was your birthday, I would have given you a gift.
          option:
            - Type 0
            - Type 1
            - Type 2
            - Type 3
          answer: Type 3
    1:
      identifier: student type 3
      quiz:
        - question: If I had read the recipe carefully, I would have cooked my dinner better.
          option:
            - He/she read the recipe carefully and cooked well.
            - He/she didn't read the recipe carefully but cooked well enough.
            - He/she read the recipe carefully but didn't cook well.
            - He/she didn't read the recipe carefully and didn't cook well enough.
          answer: He/she didn't read the recipe carefully and didn't cook well enough.
        
        - question: If I had known the answer I would not have gotten the question wrong.
          option:
            - He/she knew the answer but got the question wrong.
            - He/she knew the answer and didn't get the question wrong.
            - He/she didn't know the answer and got the question wrong.
            - He/she didn't know the answer but didn't get the question wrong.
          answer: He/she didn't know the answer and got the question wrong.
        - question: If I had known the answer I would not have asked the question.
          option:
            - He/she knew the answer but asked the question anyway.
            - He/she knew the answer so didn't ask a question.
            - He/she didn't know the answer so asked a question.
            - He/she didn't know the answer and didn't ask a question.
          answer: He/she didn't know the answer so asked a question.
        - question: I would have had a good grade, if I had worked hard.
          option:
            - He/she worked hard and got a good grade.
            - He/she didn't work hard but got a good grade anyway.
            - He/she worked hard but didn't get a good grade.
            - He/she didn't work hard and didn't get a good grade.
          answer: He/she didn't work hard and didn't get a good grade.
        - question: If I had known it was your birthday, I would have given you a gift.
          option:
            - He/she knew it was the person's birthday and gave them a gift.
            - He/she knew it was the person's birthday but didn't give them a gift.
            - He/she didn't know it was the person's birthday and didn't give them a gift.
            - He/she didn't know it was the person's birthday but gave them a gift for some other reason.
          answer: He/she didn't know it was the person's birthday and didn't give them a gift.
        
        
approach:
  jigsaw:
    0:
      identifier: approaches to negative message tone
      quiz:
        - question: "'We cannot allow you to stay here because the announcement provide that people need to pay 10 dollar for ticket.'<p>     'We would like to allow you to stay here but the announcement provide that people need to pay 10 dollar for ticket.'<p>     3.Use conditional sentences and suggest hypothetical situations" 
          option:
            - good answer
            - answer not good, or approach missing 
          answer: good answer
        - question: "'I cannot go to school today.' <p>   'I cannot go to school today because I get a bad cold and even have a fever. I am afraid of transmitting to my classmates.' <p>   2. Give clear reasons and explanations"
          option:
            - good answer
            - answer not good, or approach missing 
          answer: good answer
        - question: "If I can't get a good school, my family will hate me. <p>   If I am admitted to a good school, my family may like me a little bit.<p>3. Use conditional sentences and suggest hypothetical situations"
          option:
            - good answer
            - answer not good, or approach missing 
          answer: answer not good, or approach missing 
        - question: "'You did not submit the report this week.'  <p>   'The report was not submitted this week./I did not receive the report this week.'  <p>   1. Choose the positive, avoid the negative"
          option:
            - good answer
            - answer not good, or approach missing 
          answer: answer not good, or approach missing 
        - question: "I won't go to your party.   <p>   I will go abroad next week so I can't go to your party.<p> 2. Give clear reasons and explanations"
          option:
            - good answer
            - answer not good, or approach missing 
          answer: good answer
        - question: "We cannot allow your return on Order Number 23456        <p>  Although you have some problem about your order, our company policy only allow return within 7 days.<p> 4. Choose vocabulary with positive connotations."
          option:
            - good answer
            - answer not good, or approach missing 
          answer: answer not good, or approach missing 
        - question: "1.If you heat the ice, it melts.<p> 2.You'll get wet if it rains today.<p>3.Use conditional sentences-Allude to a hypothetical situation."
          option:
            - good answer
            - answer not good, or approach missing 
          answer: answer not good, or approach missing 
        - question: "'Do not use this court to play basketball.' <p>'Please use another court to play basketball.'  <p> 1.  Choose the positive, avoid the negative"
          option:
            - good answer
            - answer not good, or approach missing 
          answer: good answer
        - question: "1.Choose positive statements and avoid the negative.  <p>   If the price of goods falls, it will lead an increase in demand.    <p> 2.Use conditional sentences-Allude to a hypothetical situation.   <p>  You’ll get wet in the heavy rain if you forget to bring an umbrella."
          option:
            - good answer
            - answer not good, or approach missing 
          answer: answer not good, or approach missing 
